[
	{
			"//" : "Copyright 2018 Atos SE and Worldline Licensed under MIT (https://github.com/atosorigin/DevOpsMaturityAssessment/blob/master/LICENSE)",
			"SectionName" : "Introduction",
			"Questions" : [
					{
							"Type" : "Banner",
							"QuestionText" : "The goal of this questionaire is to help Gilead D&A teams assess the DevOps maturity of your team and to help you understand what might be the appropriate next steps for you on your DevOps journey.<br><br>These questions are intended to be completed for one team (typically reporting to the same line manager and usually consisting of between 5 and 15 people)."
					}
			]
	},
	{
			"SectionName" : "Team Agility",
			"SpiderPos" : 2,
			"Questions" : [
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "Does the Gilead D&A Application/Platform team have a new release/package, version of the product available every 1-2 weeks?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Checkbox",
							"QuestionText" : "Which of the following are measured by the team (tick all that apply)?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "Elapsed lead time to deliver valuable changes (from initial request to production)", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "Frequency of deployments into production", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "Change failure rate", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "Time to restore service after a failure", "Score" : 0.5}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "Does the team regularly meet to discuss what is working well, what isn't working well and what they can improve, and the top improvement items are implemented?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "Does the team take actions to ensure that the team does not create or experience bottlenecks with/for other teams?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "Yes, and the actions are effective", "Score" : 1},
									{"Answer" : "Yes, but the actions are not always effective", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "No", "Score" : 0}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "Are any work items that are blocked swiftly identified and then people collaborate to rectify the situation?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "Is there a clearly defined mechanism for prioritising the backlog?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "Does the team work on the highest priority items in the backlog?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "Are the senior team members/Architects/SMEs primarily allocated to handle most business critical or complex problems?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Checkbox",
							"QuestionText" : "Does the team have fast feedback loops in place (tick all that apply)?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "From Operations team: usually within defined SLA", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "From the SQA team: usually less than 1 day", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "From Product Owner: usually less than 2 days", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "From Business Managers: usually less than 1 week", "Score" : 0.5}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "Are there proactive steps taken to ensure there is cross train, upskill, reskill activities within the team/PODS to reduce dependencies?"
					}
			]
	},
	{
			"SectionName" : "Collaboration",
			"SpiderPos" : 7,
			"Questions" : [
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "Are knowledge and interests shared within the team and with other teams within the organisation (for example via K.E.DB, SOP, K.B.Docs, Community of Practice)?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "Yes", "Score" : 1},
									{"Answer" : "Yes, but only within the team", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "No", "Score" : 0}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "Does the team have methods in place for asynchronous communication (for example JIRA, Slack, Teams, Azure Board)?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "Do people on the team have mechanisms to collaborate with people outside of the team?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "Are people on the App/Platform team willing to work outside their usual specialism?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "Everyone on the App/Platform team is willing to do this", "Score" : 1},
									{"Answer" : "Some people on the team are willing to do this", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "Generally people on the team prefer not to do this", "Score" : 0}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "Do people on the team have a preference towards the quicker comunication/collaboration method available (e.g. Teams/Slack/Azure Board/JIRA rather than email/Phone call)?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "Everyone on the team does", "Score" : 1},
									{"Answer" : "Most people on the team do", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "Most people on the team do not", "Score" : 0}
									]                                      
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "Is there sufficient opportunity for people on the team to meet via Video Conf calls/Screenshare?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "How frequently are there misunderstandings between members of the team?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "Hardly ever", "Score" : 1},
									{"Answer" : "Fairly frequently (at least once per week)", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "Very frequently (at least once per day)", "Score" : 0}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "Do people on the team share their ideas/concerns with the rest of the team and are they fairly represented?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "Yes, always", "Score" : 1},
									{"Answer" : "Yes, most of the time", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "Hardly ever", "Score" : 0}
									]
					}
			]
	},
	{
			"SectionName" : "Automation",
			"SpiderPos" : 3,
			"Questions" : [
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "Environments",
							"QuestionText" : "Are Dev, Test, UAT, VAL environments consistent with production environments?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "Is the provisioning, configuration and management of platform/infrastructure (e.g. servers, tools, applications, user access etc.) automated (for example by using Infrastructure as Code)?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "Yes", "Score" : 1},
									{"Answer" : "Partially", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "No", "Score" : 0}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Checkbox",
							"SubCategory" : "Environments",
							"QuestionText" : "For which of these is the configuration and management of environments automated (tick all that apply)?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "Virtual machines", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "Networks/DB connectivity", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "Operating systems", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "Security, User Access Mgmt", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "Platform/System Tech-stacks", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "Test Data Provisioning/Masking", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "The applications", "Score" : 0.5}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "Environments",
							"QuestionText" : "Are the required environments (e.g. Dev, Test, Val) available in line with demand (i.e. at the right time or in a way that doesnâ€™t incur delay to activity)?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "Environments",
							"QuestionText" : "Is the provisioning, configuration and management of environments automated?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "Yes, and scaling is automatic", "Score" : 2},
									{"Answer" : "Yes, but scaling is manual", "Score" : 1},
									{"Answer" : "No", "Score" : 0}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "Testing",
							"QuestionText" : "Does the team have unit tests, static code analysis, code coverage checks in place (testing individual modules)?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "Yes, these are in place and run manually on every build", "Score" : 1},
									{"Answer" : "Yes, partially in place", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "None - does not exist", "Score" : 0}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "Testing",
							"QuestionText" : "Does the team have a high degree of automated integration tests in place (testing the interaction of modules with each other)?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "Yes, automated tests are in place and run on every build", "Score" : 1},
									{"Answer" : "Yes, automated tests are in place", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "No", "Score" : 0}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "Testing",
							"QuestionText" : "Does the team have a high degree of automated platform/system tests in place (confirming overall system functionality meets requirements)?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "Yes, automated tests are in place and run on every build", "Score" : 1},
									{"Answer" : "Yes, automated tests are in place", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "No", "Score" : 0}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "Testing",
							"QuestionText" : "Does the team have a high degree of automated performance tests in place?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "Yes, automated tests are in place and run on every build", "Score" : 1},
									{"Answer" : "Yes, automated tests are in place", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "No", "Score" : 0}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "Static Analysis",
							"QuestionText" : "Does the team complete automated security scanning of source code assets?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "Yes, automated scanning is in place and run on every build", "Score" : 1},
									{"Answer" : "Yes, automated scanning is in place", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "No", "Score" : 0}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "Static Analysis",
							"QuestionText" : "Does the team complete automated security scanning of binaries?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "Yes, automated scanning is in place and run on every build", "Score" : 1},
									{"Answer" : "Yes, automated scanning is in place", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "No", "Score" : 0}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "Static Analysis",
							"QuestionText" : "Is code automatically scanned for quality during a build?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "Yes, automated scanning is in place and run on every build", "Score" : 1},
									{"Answer" : "Yes, automated scanning is in place", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "No", "Score" : 0}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "Does failure to meet coding standards or security rules trigger a break in the build?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "Is Test Driven Development model integrated for Development & SQA integrations (e.g. automated shift-left/right)?"
					}                      
			]
	},
	{
			"SectionName" : "Architecture and Design",
			"SpiderPos" : 5,
			"Questions" : [
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "Does the architecture of the application/platform consist of loosely coupled components (choose the most accurate description)?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "It is built from a number of stateless components with scaling and resilience provided at the application layer (full MicroServices)", "Score" : 3},
									{"Answer" : "It is made up of several separate components but relies on external solutions to provide availability and scalability", "Score" : 2},
									{"Answer" : "It is largely monolithic but made up of code modules that can be worked on independently and then re-compiled into a single unit", "Score" : 1},
									{"Answer" : "It is built up of monolithic code and can only be changed in its entirety as part of a release schedule", "Score" : 0}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Checkbox",
							"QuestionText" : "Does the architecture enable Development, SQA & Ops activities to be representative and performed independently(tick all that apply)?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "There are fully separate development, test and QA environments", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "Environments are regularly re-built or synchronised (on demand)", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "Environments (non-Prod & Prod) are similar at all levels (resilience, performance, security, dependencies)", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "Each environment can be torn down and rebuilt without affecting other environments", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "Environment specific configuration items are decoupled from the code in order to accelerate rebuilds", "Score" : 0.5}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "Does the architecture enable the deployment of services independently of one another?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "Yes, every element of functionality can be updated individually and applied to the application", "Score" : 2},
									{"Answer" : "Partially, some elements can be updated independently, but there are certain core components that need to be updated together in order to maintain functionality", "Score" : 1},
									{"Answer" : "No, updates to the system need to be performed together in a formal release cycle", "Score" : 0}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "Are all application logs written to a central log repository automatically with the configuration included in the environment design to allow portability between environments?"
					}
			]
	},
	{
			"SectionName" : "DevOps Practices",
			"SpiderPos" : 6,
			"Questions" : [
					{
							"Type" : "Checkbox",
							"SubCategory" : "CI",
							"QuestionText" : "Does the team manage their source code in a central source control system (tick all that apply)?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "We have a common code repository (e.g. Git based repo)", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "We have a defined branching structure", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "We have defined repository structure", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "Our structure and branching strategy are aligned to our Dev, Test, and Prod environments (enabling a smooth flow between environments)", "Score" : 0.5}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "CI",
							"QuestionText" : "How frequently do developers integrate their code changes into master branch?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "Code is integrated at least once per day", "Score" : 2},
									{"Answer" : "Code is integrated at least weekly", "Score" : 1},
									{"Answer" : "Code is integrated infrequently but at least once a month", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "Code is integrated on an ad hoc basis when the developer feels it is ready to share", "Score" : 0}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "Code Review",
							"QuestionText" : "Is there a defined code review and approval process?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "We have a targeted code review process that is appropriate and ensures code is published in a timely manner", "Score" : 1},
									{"Answer" : "We have a code review process but the process incurs delays and hinders deployments", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "We have no code review process and bugs can frequently be integrated into the mainline (trunk)", "Score" : 0}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "CD",
							"QuestionText" : "Whenever there is a Code merge/Code commit in SCM, are automated processes triggered?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "Yes, an automated build of the software is triggered into a production-like environment, automated tests are then triggered and software is available to be automatically deployed into production", "Score" : 2},
									{"Answer" : "Yes, an automated build of the software is triggered into a production-like environment, manual tests are then performed before the release is manually deployed into production", "Score" : 1},
									{"Answer" : "Yes, an automated build of the software is triggered, however this build is then manually deployed into the relevant environments (QA and Prod)", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "No - There is no branching, merging strategy and code is built and deployed manually", "Score" : 0}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "CI",
							"QuestionText" : "Is highest priority always given to fixing a broken build?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "Yes, builds are fixed / rolled back within 10 minutes", "Score" : 2},
									{"Answer" : "Yes, builds are fixed / rolled back  within 1 hour", "Score" : 1},
									{"Answer" : "Yes, builds are fixed / rolled back  within a day", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "No", "Score" : 0}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "CI",
							"QuestionText" : "Are adequate notifications in place to communicate the build status and failures to the team (e.g. automated e-mails, slack, Teams channel)?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "CD",
							"QuestionText" : "Is it possible to roll back the application cleanly and reliably?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "Refactoring",
							"QuestionText" : "Does the team practice regular refactoring of their code?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "Yes, code is often updated independently of new functions or features to ensure technical debt is minimised", "Score" : 1},
									{"Answer" : "No, code is only updated to enable new features or functionality", "Score" : 0}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "Refactoring",
							"QuestionText" : "Is time allocated/dedicated to refactoring in order to improve code quality and reduce technical debt?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "Refactoring",
							"QuestionText" : "Are there sufficient automated regression tests in place to enable developers to refactor with confidence?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "TDD",
							"QuestionText" : "How widely does the team practice Test Driven Development (TDD), ensuring that automated tests are developed in advance of new features?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "All product code is developed using TDD", "Score" : 2},
									{"Answer" : "Some product code is developed using TDD", "Score" : 1},
									{"Answer" : "TDD is not used at all", "Score" : 0}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "TDD",
							"QuestionText" : "Is a comprehensive test framework encompassing: DB, API & UI layers used by the team?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "TDD",
							"QuestionText" : "Is automated shift-left of the Test Driven Development cycle usually applied?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "TDD",
							"QuestionText" : "Are mocks/stubs/data virtualization/automated test data management used to ensure that tests can be run quickly, frequently and repeatably?"
					}
			]
	},
	{
			"SectionName" : "Org Structure, Culture and Incentives",
			"SpiderPos" : 1,
			"Questions" : [
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "Organisation Structure",
							"QuestionText" : "Is the team a cross functional delivery team comprising of development, testing and operations expertise?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "Incentivisation",
							"QuestionText" : "Are incentives, accolades, recognitions for people on the team aligned to overall team results?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "Organisation Structure",
							"QuestionText" : "Are those responsible for designing, developing, testing and operating the application all part of the same team?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "Does the team have accountability for the product throughout its life-cycle (introduction, growth, maturity, decline)?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "Culture",
							"QuestionText" : "Does the team have a culture of experimentation and innovation?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "Culture",
							"QuestionText" : "Does the team have a high trust culture which enables autonomy?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "Incentivisation",
							"QuestionText" : "Do teams involved in developing and sustainance/support of the application/platform have aligned objectives, roadmap?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "Does the team have a self-service model in place (e.g. prioritizing work independently)?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "Organisation Structure",
							"QuestionText" : "Does the organisation's structure catalyse and support a DevOps approach?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "Is there a team charter that describes how the team behaves and works together?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "Incentivisation",
							"QuestionText" : "Is there a clear vision and purpose for the product?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "Are all the product's stakeholders identified and engaged?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "Incentivisation",
							"QuestionText" : "Is the team aligned and incentivised to a measurable business outcome?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "Do management and the wider organisation see the value in protecting time for continuous improvement?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "Does the team have enough time to learn new technologies, tools and practices?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "Organisation Structure",
							"QuestionText" : "How frequently is there interaction between the Business, Development, SQA & Ops teams?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "Business users are embedded within the team", "Score" : 2},
									{"Answer" : "The team meets with the business at least every week", "Score" : 1},
									{"Answer" : "The team meets with the business at least every month", "Score" : 0.5},
									{"Answer" : "Rarely or not at all", "Score" : 0}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "Culture",
							"QuestionText" : "Do senior stakeholders buy into and support the DevOps approach?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "Yes, we rarely have issues with business cases or bureaucratic processes", "Score" : 2},
									{"Answer" : "Yes, there is buy-in and understanding, but business processes are still too rigid", "Score" : 1},
									{"Answer" : "No", "Score" : 0}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "Culture",
							"QuestionText" : "Do members of the team practice continuous learning?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"SubCategory" : "Culture",
							"QuestionText" : "Does the team have a feedback culture (where people are happy to quickly share negative and positive feedback)?"
					}
			]
	},
	{
			"SectionName" : "Standardisation",
			"SpiderPos" : 5,
			"Questions" : [
					{
							"Type" : "Checkbox",
							"QuestionText" : "Has the organisation standardised on a set of tooling standards (tick all that apply)?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "We have a defined set of CI/CD tooling that is universally used", "Score" : 1},
									{"Answer" : "We have defined code repository tooling and standardised usage processes for them (e.g. branching pattern)", "Score" : 1},
									{"Answer" : "We have defined monitoring tooling", "Score" : 1},
									{"Answer" : "We have defined patching/upgrade tooling and processes (e.g. immutable vs. mutable)", "Score" : 1}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "Has the Gilead D&A Business Unit standardised on a set of application stacks/development languages/ETL, BI and DevOps tools?",
							"Answers" : [
									{"Answer" : "Yes, with a sufficient portfolio of options to meet our development needs", "Score" : 2},
									{"Answer" : "Yes, but with an insufficient portfolio of options to meet our development needs", "Score" : 1},
									{"Answer" : "No, any team can choose any stack/language without constraint", "Score" : 0}
									]
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "Do you envision increase usage of SaaS/Cloud Native Utility applications, eg. Azure Databricks, Power BI, Azure DevOps, other vendor products (if applicable)?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "As much as makes sense, do you use PaaS (Platform as a Service)?"
					},
					{
							"Type" : "Option",
							"QuestionText" : "As much as makes sense, do you use IaaS (Infrastructure as a Service)?"
					}
			]
	}
] 